STACY WILLIAMS



Elementary Teacher

Address 270 I S Gourley St Boise, ID 83705

Phone (570) 606-4503

Email slwilliams519@gmail.com

References

Dr. Sherry Marsh *Principal* (206) 406-4398

Victoria DeBoard Elementary Teacher (208) 615-0415

Jennifer Miller Instructional Coach (208) 284-0662

Alejandra Howell ELL Specialist (208) 954-7151

SUMMARY

Dedicated, ambitious, and goal-driven educator with experience teaching in low income, Title I schools. Creative and resourceful with proven ability to enhance student performance. Documented and quantified success in providing materials and activities that engage and challenge struggling students with intense intervention strategies.

EDUCATION

BLOOMSBURG UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA

Bachelor of Science in Education Dual Certification

- Early Childhood Education (N-3)
- Elementary Education (K-G)

Concentrations

- · Language Arts
- Special Education

BLOOMSBURG, PA

Aug. 2008-Dec. 2012 Overall GPA: 3.89 Magna Cum Laude

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SECOND GRADE TEACHER

Nampa School District #131 Sherman Elementary School Nampa, IDAHO July 2015-Present

- Collaborated in team settings to plan and teach Common Core Standards in a Title I school to students including English language learners
- Achieved proficiency and/or successful growth of 35 or more words in 94% of continuously enrolled students on the Idaho Reading Indicator Assessment (IRI)
- Designated grade level ELL teacher
- Co-taught with ELL specialist to develop and provide differentiated instruction to support growth in a class with 15 ELL students utilizing Thinking Maps
- · Utilized Journey's Common Core curriculum
- Implemented Teach Like A Champion techniques to promote student engagement
- Followed CHAMPS approach for classroom and behavior management along with PBIS while also developing individualized behavior interventions
- Conducted lessons encompassing a range of skill building activities in the four areas of language learning: Speaking, Writing, Reading, and Listening
- Progress monitored weekly to see how students were responding to interventions and assess what to do differently to create learning
- Developed common formative assessments to provide information on how students were responding to instruction
- Met with PLCs weekly to analyze data of specific targeted students and develop action plans to raise scores
- Utilized Danielson's Framework for teaching evaluation model

K-12 SUBSTITUTE TEACHER

Wyoming Area School District

EXETER, PA

February 2014 - June 2014

Fulfilled short term substitute teaching assignments across all subject areas while effectively teaching students of varied academic levels and diverse backgrounds

STACY WILLIAMS



Elementary Teacher

Address 270 I S Gourley St Boise, ID 83705

Phone (570) 606-4503

Email slwilliams519@gmail.com

References

Dr. Sherry Marsh Principal (206) 406-4398

Victoria DeBoard Elementary Teacher (208) 615-0415

Jennifer Miller Instructional Coach (208) 284-0662

Alejandra Howell ELL Specialist (208) 954-7151

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Mathematical Thinking for Instruction
 (MTI) Training with Boise State
 University Regional Math Specialists
- I Can Read Early Literacy Plan Foundational Skill Training
- Jill Jackson: How to Teach the Common Core
- ESL Co-Teaching Training with Cherry Creek School District, Colorado

STUDENT TEACHING

STUDENT TEACHER, SECOND GRADE

Pittston Area Primary Center

PITTSTON, PA

Aug. 2012-Dec. 2012

- Delivered instruction to a classroom of twenty-four students with varying abilities in six different subjects
- Implemented a variety of teaching methods to assist all students especially those with special needs
- Progress monitored students' achievements over fifteen weeks
- Adapted instructional materials, lesson plans and learning centers to meet the needs and levels of all students
- Utilized peer observation to evaluate and employ new techniques for classroom management
- Created and developed behavioral management program earning desirable tickets that were later drawn for prizes

ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

HARRISBURG URBAN PRACTICUM EXPERIENCE

Foose Elementary School

HARRISBURG, PA

May, 2011

- Implemented instruction in a first grade classroom
- Attended Professional Development workshops on various topics pertaining to curriculum and instruction
- Participated in numerous community events involving students, families, and parent volunteers

MATH TUTOR

DANVILLE, PA

St. Joseph's School

Jan. 2011- May 2011

- Worked with a small group of first grade students in an eight-week after school program
- · Assisted each individual child with after schoolwork
- Developed and implemented engaging activities to reinforce basic math skills being taught

READING TUTOR

BLOOMSBURG, PA

Bloomsburg Memorial Elementary School

Aug. 2011-Dec. 2011

- Worked one-on-one with a kindergarten student struggling with speech, letter recognition, and phonemic awareness
- · Monitored student's progress over an eight-week period
- Implemented DIBEL's and DRA assessments
- Completed case study on a kindergarten student with speech and language deficiencies